Luke Vella

Developer & Designer

Email: me@lukevella.com
Nationality: Maltese
Location: Berlin, Germany

Skills

Javascript (ES2015), HTML, CSS, ReactJS (Redux), NodeJS, Docker, webpack, Swift, Objective-C, Git, MongoDB, Cloud Foundry, Heroku, AWS.

Side Projects

react-activity

lukevella.com/react-activity

Open source library of activity indicators for react apps.

Rallly

rallly.co

Open source collaborative scheduling application.

Freeshot

freeshotapp.com

Dribbble client for iOS.

Education

University of Malta

Oct 2009 - Jun 2012

B.Sc. (Hons.) Computer Science & Artificial Intelligence

Links

Linkedin

Github

Dribbble

StackOverflow

Twitter

Summary

I am a multidisciplinary developer with over 8 years of professional experience. I've delivered multiple products to market, often overseeing projects from concept, through design and completion. My strong design background allows me to both communicate my thoughts effectively when working in a team but also work independently.

Work Experience

SAP SE - Berlin

Developer Mar 2016 - Present

- Lead the design & development of a web application aimed at processing large volumes of financial documents for the purpose of data extraction.
- Created a service—oriented architecture and introduced Docker to facilitate development and deployment of micro—services.

NOA Technologies (formerly LOCK8) - Berlin

Front-end Developer

Jun 2015 - Feb 2016

- Lead the design & development of a web based fleet management system.
- Set up workflows for development and deployment of the product across multiple environments.

Float.travel - Remote

Full-stack Developer

Sep 2014 - May 2015

- Built a native iOS application that offered free and paid walking tours.
- Developed a RESTful API that served content from a Wordpress site to the mobile application.
- Modularized the application to allow the production of a white label solution.

Zeepex – Malta

Front-end Developer

Jul 2012 - Dec 2014

- Built a single-page application that offered advanced search, data management and other tools that aimed to facilitate sourcing for recruiters.
- Developed an isomorphic javascript application that could intelligently discover social media profiles belonging to a person.

AWHPoker - Malta

Front-end Developer

Feb 2009 - Dec 2011

• Built and maintained a web application that allowed users to view information from the gaming network's back-office.